Col. Frank Slade has a very special plan for the weekend. It involves travel, women, good food, fine wine, the
tango, chauffeured limousines and a loaded forty-five. And he's bringing Charlie along for the ride.
Scent of a Woman is a drama film directed by Martin Brest.
Charlie Simms is a student at a private preparatory
school who comes from a poor family.
To earn the money for his flight home to Gresham, Oregon for Christmas,
Charlie takes a job over Thanksgiving looking after retired U.S.
Army officer Lieutenant Colonel Frank Slade, a cantankerous
middle-aged man who lives with his niece and her family.
Lt. Col. Frank Slade, played by Al Pacino.
Charlie Simms, played by Chris O'Donnell.
Mr. Trask, played by James Rebhorn.
Donna, played by Gabrielle Anwar.
George Willis, Jr., played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
W.R. Slade, played by Richard Venture.
Scent of a Woman is a 1992 American drama film produced and directed by Martin Brest that tells the story of a preparatory school student who takes a
short-term job near Thanksgiving as a companion and assistant to a retired Army lieutenant colonel who is blind, depressed and irritable.
The film was adapted by Bo Goldman from the Italian novel Il buio e il
miele (Italian: Darkness and Honey) by Giovanni Arpino.
This was previously adapted by Dino Risi for his
1974 Italian film Profumo di donna.
The American film stars Al Pacino and Chris O'Donnell, with James Rebhorn, Philip
Seymour Hoffman, Gabrielle Anwar and Bradley Whitford in supporting roles.
The film was shot primarily around New York State, and
on location at Princeton University.
Scenes were shot at the Emma Willard School, an all-girls school in Troy, New York; as well
as at the Waldorf-Astoria Hotel and the Fieldston School in New York City.
The film had a limited theatrical release on December 23, 1992 by
Universal Pictures, expanding nationwide on January 8, 1993.
It received generally positive responses from
critics and was a box-office success.
Pacino won the Academy Award for Best Actor for his performance and the film was also nominated for Best
Picture, Best Director and Best Screenplay Based on Material Previously Produced or Published.
The film won three Golden Globe Awards, for Best Screenplay,
Best Actor, and Best Motion Picture – Drama.
The film explores themes of vietnam veteran, new york city, blindness
and impaired vision, scholarship, boarding school.
The tone is emotional.